Athletic Association Records, ca. 1900-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Athletic Association Records
ca. 1900-[ongoing]
Athletic Association
RG 80 UUID:b627056a-5230-4564-b185-01fc87c0d5e8
4 boxes (1.7 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The collection contains materials that document the history of the Athletic Association, including its constitutions and bylaws, minutes, officer notes, and information on the events sponsored by the organization.
The organization was started in spring, 1893 as the Gymnasium and Field Association. The name was changed in 1915 to the Athletic Association. It originally had oversight of all inter-class sports, and later expanded to sanction inter-house and intercollegiate events as well. The group has also overseen parts of such college events as Father's Day, Field Day, Float Night, and Rally Day.
The Athletic Association records contain materials describing the history and scope of participation of the group in college events, as well as its organization, associated groups, and the changes in athletic policy at Smith College. Types of materials include student handbooks, the constitutions and bylaws, advertisements for events, other announcements, officer records and notes, minutes, and photographs.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Athletic Association records were created by the Athletic Association and donated to the College Archives.
Additional Information
Related Material
Researchers should also view:
52. Athletic Department Records
52. Physical Education Department Records
80. Athletic Subject Files
- General Files (Box 1340)
  - General 1899-c1970s (Box 1340, Folder 1)
  - Athletic Announcements and History 1900-1980 (Box 1340, Folder 2)
  - Book on Sports 1917-1925 (Box 1340, Folder 3)
  - Combined Athletic Announcements and History 1980-present (Box 1340, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets 1949-1990's (Box 1340, Folder 5)
  - Photographs 1929, 1987-1993 (Box 1340, Folder 6)
  - Tickets and Notices 1896-c1920s (Box 1340, Folder 7)
- Anniversaries 1943 (Box 1340, Folder 8)
- Awards: Notices, Invitations, etc 1996 (Box 1340, Folder 9)
- Calendar: Schedule of Events 1980-1990 (Box 1340, Folder 10)
- Conferences 1955 (Box 1340, Folder 11)
- Constitution and By-laws 1911-present (Box 1340, Folder 12)
- Father's Day (Box 1340, Folder 13)
- Friends of Smith Athletics 2002 (Box 1340, Folder 14)
- Handbooks, Students, and House reps. 1921-1962 (Box 1340, Folder 15)
- Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1900-1991 (Box 1340.1)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1900-1978 (Box 1340.1, Folder 16)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1981-1982 (Box 1340.1, Folder 17)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1983-1984 (Box 1340.1, Folder 18)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1984-1985 (Box 1340.1, Folder 19)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1985-1986 (Box 1340.1, Folder 20)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1986-1987 (Box 1340.1, Folder 21)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1987-1988 (Box 1340.1, Folder 22)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1988-1989 (Box 1340.1, Folder 23)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1989-1990 (Box 1340.1, Folder 24)
  - Intercollegiate, Combined Sports Announcements 1990-1991 (Box 1340.1, Folder 25)
  - Intercollegiate Bulletins 1980s (Box 1340.1, Folder 26)
- Intercollegiate Newsletter, The Unicorn 1982-1984 (Box 1341, Folder 1)
- Intercollegiate Schedules 1974-1989 (Box 1341, Folder 2)
- Inter-house Tournaments 1940-1949 (Box 1341, Folder 3)
- Inter-house Tournaments 1949-1951 (Box 1341, Folder 4)
- Inter-house Tournaments 1951-1963 (Box 1341, Folder 5)
- Inter-house Tournaments 1959-1970 (Box 1341, Folder 6)
- Intramural Program 1987-1988 (Box 1341, Folder 7)
- Letters and Emblems (Box 1341, Folder 8)
- Little Pioneer Club 2000-2002 (Box 1341, Folder 9)
- Minutes 1931-1936 (Box 1341, Folder 10)
- Minutes 1935-1942 (Box 1341, Folder 11)
- National Girls and Women in Sport Day 1990 (Box 1342, Folder 1)
- News Clippings 1997 (Box 1342, Folder 2)
- Newsletter, Alumnae 1974 (Box 1342, Folder 3)
- Newsletter, Pioneer Sport 1992-1994 (Box 1342, Folder 4)
- Officers 1916-1939 (Box 1342, Folder 5)
- Officers 1941-1950 (Box 1342, Folder 6)
- Officers 1950-1959 (Box 1342, Folder 7)
- Officers 1960-1968 (Box 1342, Folder 8)
- Programs 1952-1969 (Box 1342, Folder 9)
- Records, Board Member and Rep Lists 1959-1974 (Box 1342, Folder 10)
- Records, Presidents 1909-1920 (Box 1342, Folder 11)
- Records, Presidents 1960s (Box 1342, Folder 12)
- Records, Presidents 1960s (cont) (Box 1342, Folder 13)
- Records, Treasurer 1959-1970 (Box 1342, Folder 14)
- Records, Vice President 1952-1971 (Box 1342, Folder 15)